Register of the Richard V. Allen papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Campaign and transition files, 1967-1984 (Box-folder 22-24)
  - Reagan files, 1967-1984. (Box-folder 27-42)
    - Correspondence, 1975-1980 (Box-folder 27-29)
      - Alphabetical (Box-folder 27)
        - Rich Williamson, 1975-1980 (Box-folder 29: 8)
    - Statements, debates and interviews, 1977-1980 (Box-folder 29-32)
      - Reagan remarks to the Foreign Policy Association, 1977 June 9 (Box-folder 29: 9)
      - Keidanren, 1978 April 17 (Box-folder 29: 10)
      - Reagan address to the Chinese National Association of Commmerce and Industry, Taipei, Taiwan, 1978 April 21 (Box-folder 29: 11)
      - Reagan address to the Los Angeles World Affairs Council, 1978 December 14 (Box-folder 29: 12)
      - Reagan Pepperdine speech, 1979 January 12 (Box-folder 29: 13)
      - Bush news releases, 1980 (Box-folder 30: 1)
      - Miscellaneous Reagan statements, 1980 (Box-folder 30: 2)
      - Ronald Reagan selected foreign policy and defense statements, 1980 (Box-folder 30: 3)
      - Southern Republican Leadership Convention, 1980 January (Box-folder 30: 4)
      - Untitled speech, 1980 February 15 (Box-folder 30: 5)
      - Chicago Council on Foreign Relations, 1980 March 17 (Box-folder 30: 6)
      - Detroit Economic Club, 1980 May 15 (Box-folder 30: 7)
      - Ronald Reagan acceptance speech, 1980 July 17 (Box-folder 30: 8)
      - Press conference regarding Taiwan, 1980 August 16 (Box-folder 30: 9)
      - VFW speech, 1980 August 18 (Box-folder 30: 10)
      - "Strength," American Legion, 1980 August 20 (Box-folder 30: 11)
      - Foreign policy speech drafts, 1980 August 20 (Box-folder 30: 12)
      - Roundtable speech, Dallas, 1980 August 22 (Box-folder 30: 13)
      - Ronald Reagan statement on China relations, 1980 August 25 (Box-folder 30: 14)
      - Jersey City, NJ, 1980 September 1 (Box-folder 30: 15)
      - B'Nai Brith speech drafts, 1980 September 3 (Box-folder 30: 16)
      - B'Nai Brith speech, 1980 September 3. (Box-folder 30: 17)
        Includes Carter Mideast negotiation statement
      - Jacksonville, 1980 September 4 (Box-folder 30: 18)
      - Chicago International Business Council, 1980 September 9 (Box-folder 30: 19)
      - Cleveland, 1980 September 10 (Box-folder 30: 20)
      - Stealth statement, 1980 September 11 (Box-folder 30: 21)
      - Iran hostage statement, 1980 September 13 (Box-folder 31: 1)
      - Iran statement, 1980 September 13 (Box-folder 31: 2)
      - Italian American Federation, Washington D.C., 1980 September 13 (Box-folder 31: 3)
      - Conference of Presidents of Jewish Organizations, 1980 September 15 (Box-folder 31: 4)
      - Harlingen, TX, 1980 September 16 (Box-folder 31: 5)
      - Houston, TX, 1980 September 16 (Box-folder 31: 6)
      - Ronald Reagan steel statement, 1980 September 16 (Box-folder 31: 7)
      - Baltimore Debate, 1980 September 21 (Box-folder 31: 8)
      - Knoxville, TN, 1980 September 22 (Box-folder 31: 9)
      - LSU speech "Securing our Freedoms,", 1980 September 23 (Box-folder 31: 10)
      - Pepperdine speech, 1980 September 23 (Box-folder 31: 11)
      - Richard Allen/George Ball interview "Issues and Answers", 1980 September 28 (Box-folder 31: 12)
      - Reagan-Bush debate strategy, 1980 October (Box-folder 31: 13)
      - Debate preparation materials, 1980 October (Box-folder 31: 14)
      - Reagan interview Chancellor, 1980 October 3 (Box-folder 31: 15)
      - National Religious Broadcasters Association, 1980 October 3 (Box-folder 31: 16)
      - Ronald Reagan on arms control, strategic balance, east-west relations, 1980 October 7 (Box-folder 31: 17)
      - Chalfont, Lord Alun, 1980 October 7 (Box-folder 31: 18)
      - Wheaton, Illinois, 1980 October 8 (Box-folder 31: 19)
      - St. Louis, MO, 1980 October 9 (Box-folder 31: 20)
      - Allen Statement on defense, 1980 October 10 (Box-folder 31: 21)
      - Allen Stern interview, 1980 October 10 (Box-folder 31: 22)
      - Televised address, 1980 October 19 (Box-folder 31: 23)
      - Allen: Meet the Press, 1980 October 19 (Box-folder 31: 24-25)
      - Allen Press conference, NY, 1980 October 21 (Box-folder 31: 26)
      - Ronald Reagan interview, Die Welt, 1980 October 22 (Box-folder 32: 1)
      - Interview with Le Figaro, 1980 October 24 (Box-folder 32: 2)
      - Allen Washington Star, 1980 October 27 (Box-folder 32: 3)
      - Ronald Reagan - Carter debate, 1980 October 28 (Box-folder 32: 4)
      - Die Welt interview, 1980 October 31 (Box-folder 32: 5)
      - Lunch with Japanese correspondents, 1980 November (Box-folder 32: 6)
      - Reagan interviews: Stern, London Observer, London Sunday Times, 1980 November (Box-folder 32: 7)
      - Today Show interview with Brokaw and Valeriani, 1980 December 2 (Box-folder 32: 8)
      - Interview with Lesley Stahl, 1980 December 4 (Box-folder 32: 9)
      - Interview with Mark Hopkins, 1980 December 4 (Box-folder 32: 10)
    - Policy files, 1967-1984 (Box-folder 32-38)
      - Mexico, 1979 (Box-folder 32: 11)
      - Ronald Reagan position essays, 1980 (Box-folder 32: 12)
      - Allen: Secretary's Open Forum, 1980 (Box-folder 32: 13)
      - CLOSED (Box-folder 36-38)
    - Press, 1976-1981 (Box-folder 33-40)
      - Barbara Walters interview, undated (Box-folder 33: 1)
      - Clippings, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 33: 2)
      - Reagan for President press clippings, 1978-1980 (Box-folder 33: 3)
      - Announcement, 1979 November 13 (Box-folder 33: 4)
      - Reagan for President news releases, 1979 November-1980 July (Box-folder 33: 5-7)
      - Patrick Wajsman, 1980 (Box-folder 33: 8)
      - Miscellaneous press, 1980 (Box-folder 33: 9)
      - Polls, 1980 (Box-folder 33: 10)
      - German newspapers, 1980 (Box-folder 33: 11)
      - French press, 1980 (Box-folder 33: 12)
      - People's Republic of China, 1980 (Box-folder 33: 13)
      - Allen Statements and news releases, 1980 (Box-folder 33: 14)
      - Newspaper accounts of Republican National Convention, 1980 (Box-folder 33: 15-16)
      - Time, Newsweek, U.S. News and World Report, First Monday accounts of Detroit convention, 1980 (Box-folder 34: 1)
      - General campaign strategy (through immediate post-convention period), 1980 (Box-folder 34: 2)
      - Post convention roundup file, 1980 (Box-folder 34: 3-4)
      - Mother Jones, "The Institute for Policy Studies: Empire on the Left,", 1980 June/July (Box-folder 34: 5)
      - Sunday Oklahoman, "Reagan's advisors think their time has arrived,", 1980 July 20 (Box-folder 34: 6)
      - National Journal, 1980 July 26 (Box-folder 34: 7)
      - Business Week, "Reagan counts on conservatism,", 1980 July 28 (Box-folder 34: 8)
      - Jerusalem Post and Jewish Week, 1980 August (Box-folder 34: 9)
      - Japanese clippings, Nihon Keizai Shinbum, 1980 August 20 (Box-folder 34: 10)
      - Tower/Van Cleave news conference, 1980 August 23 (Box-folder 34: 11)
      - The Economist, "Going Around in Academic Circles,", 1980 August 23 (Box-folder 34: 12)
      - Des Moines Register interview, 1980 August 24 (Box-folder 34: 13)
      - Asian Wall Street Journal "An Outline of U.S. Foreign Policy Under a President Ronald Reagan,", 1980 August 29 (Box-folder 34: 14)
      - Miscellaneous clippings, 1980 August-September (Box-folder 34: 15)
      - Covert Action Information Bulletin, 1980 August-September (Box-folder 34: 16)
      - "Stealth Security Data Leak,", 1980 September (Box-folder 34: 17)
      - Allen interview with Stern, 1980 September (Box-folder 34: 18)
      - Media coverage of Reagan Detroit appearance, 1980 September 2 (Box-folder 34: 19)
      - Detroit News, "Adviser Opposes Reagan Trade Stand,", 1980 September 28 (Box-folder 34: 20)
      - Congressional Quarterly, 1980 October 4 (Box-folder 34: 21)
      - Miscellaneous clippings, 1980 October (Box-folder 34: 22)
      - "October Surprise,", 1980 October (Box-folder 34: 23)
      - Reagan/Bush press conference on SALT, 1980 October 20 (Box-folder 34: 24)
      - Clippings from the New York Times, Washington Post, New York Post, and Christian Science Monitor, 1980 October (Box-folder 34: 25)
      - The Economist "A Winning Team?", 1980 October (Box-folder 34: 26)
      - William Van Cleave statements on Reagan defense spending plans, 1980 October 27 (Box-folder 34: 27)
      - New York Times and Christian Science Monitor clippings, 1980 October 29 (Box-folder 34: 28)
      - Clippings, 1981 (Box-folder 34: 29)
      - CLOSED (Box-folder 39-40)
    - Transition files, 1973-1981 (Box-folder 35-42, 89)
      - General (Box-folder 35)
      - Transition Team phone numbers, undated (Box-folder 35: 1)
      - Reference booklet on conflicts of interest, undated (Box-folder 35: 2-3)
      - China briefing book, undated (Box-folder 35: 4-5)
      - DOD plum book, undated (Box-folder 35: 6-7)
      - ACDA transition team final report, 1980 (Box-folder 35: 8)
      - Scranton report on U.S. - Soviet relations, 1980 (Box-folder 35: 9)
      - Recommendations for the Reagan Administration, 1980 (Box-folder 35: 10)
      - Classified Tabs/Briefing Book, 1980 (Box-folder 35: 11)
      - U.S. government policy and supporting positions, 1980 (Box-folder 89)
      - CLOSED (Box-folder 41-42)
- White House Files, 1979-1989 (Box-folder 43-53)
  Contains correspondence, clippings, schedules, notes, press releases and statements dating from Allen's service under President Reagan on as National Security Advisor. Arranged in 6 subseries: Administrative files, 1981; Memoranda and correspondence, 1981; Trips and visits, 1981; Press briefings and clippings, 1980-1981; Policy files, 1979-1989; and Controversy and resignation files, 1981-1982. Within each subseries, files are arranged in reverse chronological order. See also Declassified U.S. government records
  - Administrative files, 1981 (Box-folder 43-44)
    - Telephone lists, 1981 (Box-folder 43: 1-7)
    - Schedule, 1981 May-November (Box-folder 43: 8-11)
    - Schedule, 1981 January-April (Box-folder 44: 1-3)
    - Schedule - Vice President, 1981 March-December (Box-folder 44: 4-7)
    - Schedule - President's Monthly, 1981 (Box-folder 44: 8)
    - Schedule - President's Weekly, 1981 (Box-folder 44: 9)
    - Schedule - President's Daily, 1981 (Box-folder 44: 10-12)
  - Memoranda and correspondence, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 45-46)
    - Memoranda for the President, 1981 (Box-folder 45: 1-2)
    - Adelman, Ken, 1981 (Box-folder 45: 3)
    - Allen to the White House Staff, 1981 (Box-folder 45: 4)
    - Allen Conversation with Bessmertnykh, 1981 September 8 (Box-folder 45: 5)
    - Allen family correspondence, 1981 (Box-folder 45: 6)
    - Anderson, Jack, 1981 (Box-folder 45: 7)
    - Bahr, Egon, 1981 (Box-folder 45: 8)
    - Baldrige, Malcolm, 1981 (Box-folder 45: 9)
    - Bandar, Prince Sultan, 1981 (Box-folder 45: 10)
    - Brady, Jim, 1981 (Box-folder 45: 11)
    - Brzezinski, Zbigniew, 1981 (Box-folder 45: 12)
    - Burns, Dr. Arthur, 1981 (Box-folder 45: 13)
    - Returns from the Vice President, 1981 (Box-folder 45: 14)
    - Carter letter to the President, 1981 Sept. 9 (Box-folder 45: 15)
    - Countess of Romanones, Aline, 1981 (Box-folder 45: 16)
    - Crozier, Brian, 1981 (Box-folder 45: 17)
    - Cutler, Lloyd, 1981 (Box-folder 45: 18)
    - Fernandez, Benjamin, 1981 (Box-folder 45: 19)
    - Epstein, Edward Jay, 1981 (Box-folder 45: 20)
    - Fielding, Fred, 1981 (Box-folder 45: 21)
    - Fonda, Jane, 1981 (Box-folder 45: 22)
    - Fontaine, Roger, 1981 (Box-folder 45: 23)
    - Friedrich, Paul J., 1981 (Box-folder 45: 24)
    - Haig, Alexander, 1981 (Box-folder 45: 25)
    - Hammer, Armand, 1981 (Box-folder 45: 26)
    - Hannaford, Peter D., 1981 (Box-folder 45: 27)
    - Helms, Richard, 1981 March 19 (Box-folder 45: 28)
    - Hickey, Edward V. Jr., Includes photograph, 1981 April 19 (Box-folder 45: 29)
    - Johnson, Donald, 1981 (Box-folder 45: 30)
    - Kelly, J.B., 1981 February (Box-folder 45: 31)
    - Kirkpatrick, Ambassador Jeanne, 1981 (Box-folder 45: 32)
    - Kohl, Helmut, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 45: 33)
    - Kissinger, Henry A., 1981 (Box-folder 46: 1)
    - Korea Correspondence, 1981 (Box-folder 46: 2)
    - Kraft, Joseph, 1981 (Box-folder 46: 3)
    - LeBailly, E.B. Lt. Gen. USAF, 1981 (Box-folder 46: 4)
    - Lehman, John, 1981 (Box-folder 46: 5)
    - Lilley, James, 1981 (Box-folder 46: 6)
    - Margáin, Hugo (Mexico), 1981 March 5 (Box-folder 46: 7)
    - Meese, Edwin III, 1981 (Box-folder 46: 8)
    - Mitterrand, 1981 (Box-folder 46: 9)
    - Naumann, Michael, 1981 (Box-folder 46: 10)
    - Neumann, Robert, 1981 (Box-folder 46: 11)
    - Nixon, Richard M., 1981 (Box-folder 46: 14)
    - Noble, Ed, 1981 (Box-folder 46: 13)
    - Pendleton, James E., 1981 (Box-folder 46: 14)
    - Pipes, Richard E., 1981 (Box-folder 46: 17)
    - Returns from the President, 1981 (Box-folder 46: 16)
    - Letter to Reagan from President Chiang Ching-Kuo of Taiwan, 1980 November 5 (Box-folder 46: 17)
    - Letter from Reagan to President of Pakistan, 1981 September 4 (Box-folder 46: 18)
    - Letter from Reagan to King Kahalid of Saudi Arabia, 1981 Aug 19 (Box-folder 46: 19)
    - Letter to the President from the Sultan of Oman, 1981 March 7 (Box-folder 46: 20)
    - Rostow, Eugene, 1981 (Box-folder 46: 21-22)
    - Shcaransky, Mrs. Avital, 1981 (Box-folder 46: 23)
    - Shultz, George P., 1981 (Box-folder 46: 24)
    - Sick, Gary, 1981 (Box-folder 46: 25)
    - Taguchi, Takao, 1981 (Box-folder 46: 26)
    - Toyoda, Shoichiro, 1981 (Box-folder 46: 27)
    - Trudeau, 1981 (Box-folder 46: 28)
    - Von Nordheim, Manfred, 1981 (Box-folder 46: 29)
    - Wick, Charles Z., 1981 (Box-folder 46: 30)
    - Weinberger, Caspar, 1981 (Box-folder 46: 31)
  - Trips and visits, 1981 (Box-folder 47)
    - Prime Minister Seaga visit, 1981 Jan. 28 (Box-folder 47: 1)
    - Visit of Prime Minister Thatcher to U.S., 1981 February (Box-folder 47: 2)
    - Pope John Paul's visit to Alaska, 1981 February 26 (Box-folder 47: 3)
    - Canada trip, 1981 March (Box-folder 47: 4-5)
    - Visit of former Prime Minister Fukuda, 1981 March 20 (Box-folder 47: 6)
    - Japanese Prime Minister Suzuki visit, 1981 May 7-8 (Box-folder 47: 7)
    - Visit of H.E. Jose Lopez Portillo, 1981 June (Box-folder 47: 8)
    - Reagan visit to the economic summit, Ottawa, Canada, 1981 July (Box-folder 47: 9)
    - Visit of Anwar Sadat to the U.S., 1981 August (Box-folder 47: 10)
    - Trip to Paris and Bonn, 1981 September 3-6 (Box-folder 47: 11-14)
    - Cancun summit, Mexico, 1981 October 22-23 (Box-folder 47: 15)
    - King Hussein Visit, 1981 October-November (Box-folder 47: 16)
    - Luggage tags, 1981 (Box-folder 47: 17)
  - Press briefings and clippings, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 48-49)
    - Brief: European Journalists, 1981 November 25 (Box-folder 48: 1)
    - Background Brief: Venezuelan press, 1981 November 17 (Box-folder 48: 2)
    - Background Brief: Campins of Venezuela visit, 1981 November (Box-folder 48: 3)
    - Meese, Allen, Israeli Knesset members meeting, 1981 November 11 (Box-folder 48: 4)
    - Briefing with J. Baker, AWACS, 1981 October 29 (Box-folder 48: 5)
    - Briefing: PFIAB, Schweitzer, 1981 October 20 (Box-folder 48: 6)
    - Briefing: Mitterand/Yorktown, 1981 October 16 (Box-folder 48: 7)
    - Briefing: President's WAC speech, 1981 October 14 (Box-folder 48: 8)
    - Background Brief: WAC speech and Cancun, 1981 October 14 (Box-folder 48: 9)
    - Background Brief: King Juan Carlos visit, 1981 October 13 (Box-folder 48: 10)
    - Background Brief: Juan Carlos preview and Sadat, 1981 October 9 (Box-folder 48: 11)
    - Brief, 1981 September 23 (Box-folder 48: 12)
    - Brief: AWACS, 1981 September 22 (Box-folder 48: 13)
    - Brief: President's meeting with President Duarte (El Salvador), 1981 September 21 (Box-folder 48: 14)
    - Background Brief for Begin, 1981 September 8-9 (Box-folder 48: 15)
    - Background Brief: Sadat visit, 1981 August 5 (Box-folder 49: 1)
    - Background Briefing: New Zealand, 1981 July 24 (Box-folder 49: 2)
    - Briefing: President's meeting with Prime Minister Thatcher, Ottawa Summit, 1981 July 20 (Box-folder 49: 3)
    - Background Briefing Trudeau visit, 1981 July 10 (Box-folder 49: 4)
    - Briefing: President's Meeting with U.S. Business Committee on Jamaica, 1981 July 2 (Box-folder 49: 5)
    - Briefing: President's Meeting with Prime Minister Fraser of Australia, 1981 June 30 (Box-folder 49: 6)
    - Briefing: Israel/Iraq, 1981 June 11 (Box-folder 49: 7)
    - Briefing: Lopez Portillo visit, 1981 June 8 (Box-folder 49: 8)
    - Briefing: Schmidt visit, 1981 May 20-21 (Box-folder 49: 9)
    - Brief: Mexican Journalists, 1981 May 19 (Box-folder 49: 10)
    - Brief: French Elections, 1981 May 11 (Box-folder 49: 11)
    - Brief: Suzuki Visit, 1981 May 5-8 (Box-folder 49: 12)
    - Briefing: Foreign Investment Conference, 1981 May 4 (Box-folder 49: 13)
    - Briefing: Grain Embargo, 1981 April 24 (Box-folder 49: 14)
    - Briefing: F-14/AWAC, 1981 April 23 (Box-folder 49: 15)
    - Background Briefing: Canada, 1981 March 6 (Box-folder 49: 16)
    - Miscellaneous press briefings and pool reports, 1981 (Box-folder 49: 17)
    - Pete Hamill, LEAR's "Thank you Nancy,", 1988 (Box-folder 49: 18)
    - Haig "Guerrilla Campaign" clippings, 1981 Nov. 3-8 (Box-folder 49: 19)
    - Washington Post - Elizabeth Bumiller, 1981 June 28 (Box-folder 49: 20)
    - Time: Man of the Year, 1981 January 5 (Box-folder 49: 21)
    - Le Figaro, 1980 November 8 (Box-folder 49: 22)
    - Election Issues: Time, Newsweek, U.S. News and World Report, 1980 (Box-folder 49: 23-24)
  - Policy files, 1979-1989 (Box-folder 50-51)
    - Executive order setting up a commission on broadcasting to Cuba, 1981 September 23 (Box-folder 50: 1)
    - Bipartisan Plans for Tax and Spending Restraint, 1981 June (Box-folder 50: 2)
    - Reagan statement on grain embargo, 1981 April 24 (Box-folder 50: 3)
    - Program for economic recovery, 1981 February 18 (Box-folder 50: 4)
    - AWACS/F-15/F-16, 1981 (Box-folder 50: 5-8)
    - AWACS material binder, 1981 (Box-folder 50: 9)
    - CLOSED (Box-folder 51)
  - Controversy and resignation files, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 51-53)
    - CLOSED (Box-folder 51-53)
- Subject files, 1968-1999 (Box-folder 54-58)
  Correspondence, clippings, speeches, lists, and notes regarding subjects of interest to Allen or people he worked with. Topics of note include the Iran hostage crisis and Presidents Nixon, Reagan, and G.H.W. Bush. Arranged alphabetically.
  - Bush, George H. W., 1986-1998 (Box-folder 54: 1)
  - Iran Hostage Crisis, 1980-1993 (Box-folder 54: 2-9)
  - Iran Hostage Crisis: A.A. Mohammed meeting, 1980 September 10 (Box-folder 54: 10)
  - Iran Hostage Crisis: ABC XYZ (anonymous source), 1980 (Box-folder 54: 11)
  - Iran Hostage Crisis: All Fall Down by Gary Sick, 1985 (Box-folder 54: 12)
  - Iran Hostage Crisis: Allen/Casey travel, 1980 (Box-folder 55: 1)
  - Iran Hostage Crisis: Barbara Honegger, 1988 (Box-folder 55: 2)
  - Iran Hostage Crisis: Casey documents, 1980 (Box-folder 55: 3)
  - Iran Hostage Crisis: Casey telephone notes, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 55: 4)
  - Iran Hostage Crisis: Correspondence, 1991 (Box-folder 55: 5)
  - Iran Hostage Crisis: Cutler article, 1991 (Box-folder 55: 6)
  - Iran Hostage Crisis: Dan Finn luncheon meeting, 1991 December 19 (Box-folder 55: 7)
  - Iran Hostage Crisis: Flora Lewis, 1987 (Box-folder 55: 8)
  - Iran Hostage Crisis: Gang of ten/October surprise group, 1980 (Box-folder 55: 9)
  - Iran Hostage Crisis: Gary Sick, 1981 (Box-folder 55: 10)
  - Iran Hostage Crisis: George Bush October schedule and accompanying news stories, 1980 (Box-folder 55: 11)
  - Iran Hostage Crisis: Jamshid Hashemi, 1999 (Box-folder 55: 12)
  - Iran Hostage Crisis: Joint Report of the Task Force, 1993 January 3 (Box-folder 55: 13)
  - Iran Hostage Crisis: Meetings and telephone notes, 1980-1991 (Box-folder 55: 14)
  - Iran Hostage Crisis: Miscellaneous, 1980-1992 (Box-folder 55: 15)
  - Iran Hostage Crisis: Notes, 1992 (Box-folder 55: 16)
  - Iran Hostage Crisis: October surprise, 1991, 1998 (Box-folder 56: 1)
  - Iran Hostage Crisis: October Surprise clippings, 1980-1992 (Box-folder 56: 2-3)
  - Iran Hostage Crisis: Peter Rodman article, 1981 (Box-folder 56: 4)
  - Iran Hostage Crisis: Press packets, 1992 (Box-folder 56: 5)
  - Iran Hostage Crisis: Schedules/calendar, 1980 (Box-folder 56: 6)
  - Iran Hostage Crisis: Silberman letters, 1987-1997 (Box-folder 56: 7)
  - Iran Hostage Crisis: U.S.A. versus Richard Brenneke subpoena, 1986-1990 (Box-folder 56: 8)
  - Iran Hostage Crisis: U.S.A. versus Richard Brenneke, 1980-1990 (Box-folder 56: 9)
  - Iran Hostage Statements, 1980 (Box-folder 56: 10)
  - Nixon, Richard M., 1971-1999 (Box-folder 56: 11-12)
  - Nixon clippings and speeches, 1968-1993 (Box-folder 56: 13-14)
  - Reagan biographical sketch, 1984 (Box-folder 57: 1)
  - Reagan building, 1995-1998 (Box-folder 57: 2)
  - Reagan Building dedication, 1998 March-May (Box-folder 57: 3-4)
  - Reagan campaign policy advisors, 1980 (Box-folder 57: 5)
  - Reagan campaign statement, 1980 (Box-folder 57: 6)
  - Reagan defense policy advisors, 1980 (Box-folder 57: 7)
  - Reagan - Mementos, Includes photographs, 1981-1986 (Box-folder 57: 8-10)
  - Reagan, Nancy correspondence, 1996-1999 (Box-folder 57: 11)
  - Reagan press clippings, 1980-1999 (Box-folder 57: 12-13)
  - Reagan, Ronald W., 1982-1999 (Box-folder 58: 1-4)
  - Reagan strategy for peace memo, 1978 (Box-folder 58: 5)
  - United States Institute of Peace papers, 1997 December (Box-folder 58: 6)
- Committee files, 1969-1984 (Box-folder 59-61)
  Correspondence, drafts, speeches, clippings, lists, and notes documenting Allen's work with various councils and committees. Topics include economics, international trade, and the Republican National Committee. Arranged in two subseries: Council on International Economic Policy File, 1969-1972 and Republican National Committee, 1976-1984. Each subseries is arranged in chronological order.
  - Council on International Economic Policy files, 1969-1972 (Box-folder 59)
    - Richard Nixon message to Congress on trade policy, 1969 November 18 (Box-folder 59: 1)
    - Letter from Albert L. Williams, Chairman, 1970 May 1 (Box-folder 59: 2)
    - Announcement of Allen appointment, 1970 May 21 (Box-folder 59: 3)
    - Visits to Japan, 1971 March, October (Box-folder 59: 4)
    - Press regarding Allen appointment, 1971 July (Box-folder 59: 5)
    - Trip to Azores, 1971 July (Box-folder 59: 6)
    - Organization of the council, 1971 September (Box-folder 59: 7)
    - Drafts, 1971 (Box-folder 59: 8)
    - Speeches (Economy), 1971 (Box-folder 59: 9)
    - Schedule proposals, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 59: 10)
    - Peter G. Peterson, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 59: 11)
    - Lists, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 59: 12)
    - Correspondence, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 59: 13-16)
    - Press, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 59: 17-19)
    - Visit to Japan, 1972 January (Box-folder 59: 20)
  - Republican National Committee, 1976-1984 (Box-folder 60-61)
    - CLOSED (Box-folder 60-61)
- Speeches and writings, 1961-1999 (Box-folder 62-73)
  Includes speeches, articles, interviews, debates, and book drafts written by Allen. Also includes correspondence, notes, and clippings regarding speaking engagements and writings. Topics include trade policy, foreign policy, Ronald Reagan, and George H. W. Bush. Recordings of interviews in this series may also be included in the Audiovisual Materials series. Arranged in chronological order.
  - Graduation speeches, undated (Box-folder 62: 1)
  - Dissertation, undated (Box-folder 62: 2-4)
  - Dissertation, In German, undated (Box-folder 62: 5-7)
  - Article on religion, Estudios Politicos, 1961 (Box-folder 62: 8)
  - Lectures on political theory, Georgia Institute of Technology, 1962 (Box-folder 62: 9-10)
  - Article in Europa Archiv, 1964 (Box-folder 62: 11)